<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News &amp; Updates | Human Behaviour and Energy Laboratory (HuBEL)</title>
    <link>https://www.gyyun.org/news/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.gyyun.org/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>News &amp; Updates</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.gyyun.org/media/icon_hu_8ea7b59fd4231cba.png</url>
      <title>News &amp; Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.gyyun.org/news/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>HuBEL Strengthens Its Research Team with New Members</title>
      <link>https://www.gyyun.org/news/2025-08-new-publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gyyun.org/news/2025-08-new-publication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Human Behaviour and Energy Laboratory (HuBEL) at Kyung Hee University is pleased to
announce the expansion of our team. On September 1st, we were delighted to welcome &lt;strong&gt;Ali
Muzahir, Ayeen M. Khan, Da Eun Jung, and Lewis Nsengeyukuri&lt;/strong&gt; to our lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the leadership of Professor Geun Young Yun, HuBEL continues to build on its strong
foundation of interdisciplinary research. The addition of our new members brings valuable new
skills and diverse perspectives that will enhance our ongoing work to understand human
behaviour and advance sustainable energy and climate solutions at building and urban scales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This growth marks an exciting new phase for the lab. The fusion of our established expertise
with fresh insights will invigorate our collaborative environment and accelerate our progress in
tackling complex global challenges. By expanding our team, we are reinforcing our commitment
to producing innovative, high-impact research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are confident that the contributions of our new colleagues will be instrumental as we
continue to push the boundaries of knowledge. We look forward to a future of shared success
and groundbreaking discoveries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the team!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Lab&#39;s New AI Model Tackles Missing Data in Building Energy Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.gyyun.org/news/2025-09-new-research-grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gyyun.org/news/2025-09-new-research-grant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce the publication of our latest research, &amp;lsquo;Adaptive neural temporal
hybridization for missing data imputation in building energy use datasets: An integrated LNN-
LSTM weighted model&amp;rsquo;, in the prestigious Journal of Building Engineering. This work, led by
Saeed Murtaza, Sarath Raj, and Prof. Geun Young Yun, introduces a groundbreaking approach
to a persistent challenge in building energy management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Problem: Incomplete Data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effective energy management in buildings relies on accurate, continuous data. However, due to
sensor malfunctions or communication errors, energy consumption data is often incomplete.
These gaps can significantly impair the performance of data-driven systems used for forecasting
energy demand and optimizing efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Solution: The Integrated LNN-LSTM Weighted Model (ILLWM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this challenge, our research team developed a novel deep learning model called the
Integrated LNN-LSTM Weighted Model (ILLWM). This innovative model combines the strengths
of two powerful neural networks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;● Liquid Neural Networks (LNN): Known for their flexibility and ability to adapt to
dynamically changing data streams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;● Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) Networks: Excel at recognizing and modeling long-
term patterns in time-series data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ILLWM uses an intelligent, RMSE-based weighting system to dynamically combine the
outputs of both LNN and LSTM, leveraging the best capabilities of each to produce a single,
highly accurate estimate for the missing data points.
Key Findings and Impact&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tested the ILLWM on real-world energy consumption data from commercial, residential, and
hospital buildings, even with high rates of missing data (up to 40%). The results were
remarkable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our model significantly outperformed existing imputation methods. For instance, in a
commercial building dataset with 40% missing data, the ILLWM reduced imputation errors by
89.6% compared to a standard LSTM model and 76.9% compared to a standalone LNN
model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By ensuring more complete and reliable datasets, the ILLWM can directly enhance the accuracy
of energy demand forecasting and support the development of more sustainable and efficient
energy management strategies in buildings worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the Full Paper&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We congratulate the authors on this significant contribution to the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authors: Saeed Murtaza, Sarath Raj, Geun Young Yun, Duk-Joon Park, Ji-Hye Kim,
Gwanyong Park, and Jin Woo Moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full paper is available in the Journal of Building Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DOI: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jobe.2025.113774&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jobe.2025.113774&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
